Anders Brujordet

Lead DevOps Engineer

I started out as a Java consultant focusing on Clean Code and agile methodologies, but I quickly got fascinated by the power and elegance of functional programming with Scala. This lead me to Finn where I got to learn more from the API team consisting of excelent scala developers. At Finn I also tried to improve the CI/CI platform and in doing so I got noticed by Schibsted, Finn's parent company. I was hired to be part of the Delivery team in Schibsted to provide a delivery Platform for 1500 developers. When the door to "DevOps" was finally opened many of it's areas caught my interest, and I later joined VPS to help them create a Delivery Platform from scratch while also focusing on improving security. Now I'm the Lead DevOps Engineer at Piano working on improving our Delivery tooling.

At home I'm a dad, husband, power lifter, guitarist and hobby tinkerer. The latter might be why DevOps and security resonate so well with me, as I love to take things a part and create new stuff. I've created my own MagicMirror which displays among other things the next train to leave from my local station. I've built, soldered and programmed my own silenced mechanical keyboard which I use every day both at home and at work. And when kubernetes was made available I was quick to create my own cluster at home using Raspberry pis and Lego. All my computers and network utilities report metrics and logs using Prometheus, Grafana and Loki, so the homelab has grown guite a bit.



Experience

2020 - **∞** Lead DevOps Engineer - Piano

At Piano I'm working on streamlining the delivery process by creating a golden path, which all teams can follow. The entire pipeline from source code to delivery is covered by this path be it bare metal deployments of heavy data processing applications or micro services headed for kubernetes. In this role I also focus on improving and highlighting security best practises and engineering productivity.

Key technologies: Gitlab, Bazel, Bazel Buildfarm, Kubernetes, Flux, Java

2019 - 2020 CI/CD Platform Lead - Verdipapirsentralen

At VPS I worked on implementing a full Delivery Platform for one of Norway's most critical financial institutions. I owned the full CI/CD pipelines including code storage, build, code analysis, deployments and engineering productivity. I also contributed in other teams where needed and strive to provide general security improvements.

Key technologies: Jenkins, OpenShift, Ruby, JavaScript, Java

2016 - 2019 Tech Lead & Senior Software Engineer - Schibsted

I was brought into Schibsted to help create a global Delivery Platform for 1500 developers. My initial role included developing and running Spinnaker for multi cloud deployment pipelines, and utilizing Travis and Artifactory to optimize for speed and resiliency. I was later made the tech lead and technical product owner for CI. The responsibility of the Delivery team was to enable Schibsted's developers to quickly build, test, deploy and manage their services regardless of location, tech stack and cloud provider.

Key technologies: Spinnaker, Travis, Java, Groovy, Python, JavaScript, AWS, Google Cloud and Kubernetes.

2014 - 2016 Senior Developer - Finn.no

I joined Finn to be part of their renowned API team which are know to be excellent Scala developers. I learned a lot from them while developing and maintaining Finn's internal and public API. After a while I started investing more time in their Delivery Platform and especially focusing on the CI/CD part for databases and Varnish cache.

Key technologies: Scala, SBT, python, varnish

2011 - 2014 Java Consultant - Knowit

As a consultant at Knowit it got to work on one of Norway's earliest DevOps driven projects with the Oslo municipality. I also got a taste for the Scala programming language working for Kommuneforlaget, where we created a data warehouse from scratch. Key technologies: Java, Scala, maven, ruby, Spring, git

2010 - 2011 Java Consultant - SiriusIT

As an engineer in "NAV - Pensjonpgrammet" I took part in development and testing of the governmental letter templating system which was a part of Norway's largest IT project to date.

Key technologies: Java, Scrum, Python

Training

2013

Functional Programming Principles in Scala - Coursera

The class gives an introduction into functional programming in Scala. The class is taught by Martin Odersky, the creator of Scala, and was completed within the given time with a score of "89.6% with distinction".

2010 Oracle Certified Java Programmer 6 - Oracle

Education 2008 - 2010

Master of Computer Science - NTNU

The program focused on all aspects of data retrieval and storage, resulting in a master thesis on <u>Finding an Optimal Approach</u> for Indexing <u>DNA Sequences</u>

2005 - 2008 Bachelor of Computer Science - NTNU

A broad focus on all aspects of computer science included programming, databases, operating systems, networking data structures and algorithms.

Contact

E-mail

anders@brujordet.no

Blog

blog.brujordet.no

Skills

Backend



Frontend

••••



00000

Cloud

00000

Network

••••

Security

00000

Design

●0000